



## LINKS



tfmcmahon.com



tfmcmahon@gmail.com



561 602 0440



Chicago, IL



# **TECHNOLOGY**

- JAVASCRIPT
- NODE.JS
- EXPRESS
- MONGOOSE
- REACT
- REDUX
- JEST
- HTML
- CSS



#### CONNECT



linkedin.com/in/tfmcmahon



github.com/tfmcmahon



glitch.com/@tfmcmahon



codepen.io/tfmcmahon



Recent coding bootcamp graduate with 10+ years of experience as an award-winning digital artist. Excited to turn my focus to new challenges in a software development role. Eager to join a team in a technical capacity that I can both learn from and contribute to in a meaningful way.

Extensive experience collaborating with others to achieve the highest quality results within project deadlines, regularly navigating and overcoming challenges and obstacles. Comfortable working alone or with a team on multiple projects concurrently.



### TECHNICAL PROJECTS =

• POSTER SHOP // full-stack e-commerce app 💿

Digital store front: search, filter by category, or view related posters.

Back-end written in Node & Express with asyncronous code. Utilized Mongoose subdocuments for organization and virtual fields for password hashing.

Front-end written in React. Integrates Braintree as a third-party payment processing system.

Using Jest as a testing framework, wrote back-end unit and integration tests. Set up seeded, local database instances for testing.

• TWITCH VIEWER // front-end React + Redux app 🖎

Browse Twitch.tv after connecting an existing account; search by streamer or by game.

Written with React hooks. Global state management using Redux.

Integrates with several Twitch API end points via the OAuth2 workflow.

• ISSUE TRACKER // full-stack MERN app 🖎

Multi-user project and issue collaboration. Project collaborators can create, update, close, and delete issues, each with editable titles, desciptions, and statuses.

User authentication implemented with JSON web tokens and bcrypt in Express. Deployed with Heroku.



### **EXPERIENCE**

• SENIOR CGI ARTIST // GIANNINI CREATIVE. 2008 - CURRENT

**Collaborate:** work with agency art directors and producers to create artwork that meets or exceeds client expectations. Comfortable in a client-facing role; both giving and receiving feedback.

**Lead:** hire and motivate talent. Plan, follow-up, and evaluate deliverables in order to ensure project objectives are met.

Adapt: regularly achieve proficiency with new software to meet project technical demands.

Excell: started as an intern in 2008, promoted to CGI Artist in 2009, and Senior CGI Artist in 2016.

• LEAD ARTIST // WILD GUESS SOFTWARE, 2015 - 2017

**Problem solve:** worked with the lead engineer to identify and overcome all technical, performance, and pipeline hurdles.

Ship: Blackfaun, a Roguelike-Action-Role-Playing-Game, was released on Steam in late 2017.



# **EDUCATION** •

• FREE CODE CAMP // OCT 2019 - JAN 2020

**Full Stack Certification:** JavaScript algorithms and data structures, Front end with React and Redux, API and microservices, Information security and QA.

• FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY // 2004 - 2008

**Bachelor of Fine Arts:** Computer Arts in Animation with a specialization in character rigging Honors - Magna Cum Laude (GPA 3.8 / 4.0).